<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[jr0cket - community developer]]></title>
  <link href="http://jr0cket.github.io/octopress-project/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jr0cket.github.io/octopress-project/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-04T18:07:27+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://jr0cket.github.io/octopress-project/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[John Stevenson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creating Blog Posts With Octopress]]></title>
    <link href="http://jr0cket.github.io/octopress-project/blog/2014/03/04/creating-blog-posts-with-octopress/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-04T15:46:14+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://jr0cket.github.io/octopress-project/blog/2014/03/04/creating-blog-posts-with-octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Octopress provides an easy way to create blog posts by proving a task that will automatically place and name your markdown file.  This helps manage your blog posts in a sensible structure and avoids conflicts.</p>

<p>To create a new post, use the following command inside your Octopress project folder:</p>

<p>rake new_post[&ldquo;Title of your blog post&rdquo;]</p>

<p>This will create a markdown file including frontmatter to apply the blog post style.  The task creates the file under the _source folder and included the date at the start of the filename.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Now you can edit the file and simply add your content.  Once you have written your blog post you can ask Octopress to generate the html for your new post.</p>

<p>rake generate</p>

<p>You can view the results locally, or simply deploy up to your chosen location (eg. github pages)</p>

<p>rake preview  ;; is that correct ??
rake deploy</p>

<h2>Adding images</h2>

<p>Images are always a good way to explain concepts or to just get attendtion for your writing.</p>

<p>To add an image to your post, you add the following code</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span>[Insert an image in your post]</span><a href='http://octopress.org/docs/plugins/image-tag/'>link</a></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>&lt;img class="[class names]" src="http://jr0cket.github.io/octopress-project/path/to/image" title="[width] [height] [title text [alt text]]" ></span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Here is an example with my two cute cats:</p>

<p><img src="http://jr0cket.github.io/octopress-project/images/kittens-snuggled.png"></p>

<p>Thank you</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Blog Post Ever - Awesome]]></title>
    <link href="http://jr0cket.github.io/octopress-project/blog/2014/03/03/first-blog-post-ever-awesome/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-03T00:08:42+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://jr0cket.github.io/octopress-project/blog/2014/03/03/first-blog-post-ever-awesome</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is the first blog post of many in my adventures in learning how to publish a blog using Octopress.</p>

<p>As a developer I want a lightweight tool to create and easily publish content interesting to other developers in the community.  Although I can write HTML, CSS and JavaScript for webapps, I dont want to be slowed down writing these things when I am doing creative writing.</p>

<p>Using Octopress, which is a blogging framework on top of Jekyll, I can write my content using Markdown.  As Markdown is just simple text with a few characters and indents used for formating, I can focus on the writing and make it as appealing as I can.  I dont get distracted by the visual layout of the content and a standard design for the blog is consistently applied.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The only challenge I had intially was to get a working copy of Ruby running on my Ubuntu laptop.  Jekyll and therefore Octopress requires Ruby version 1.9.3 or greater and Unfortunately I seemed to have a mix of 1.9.1 and 1.9.3.  In Ubuntu 13.10 there is a strange stiuation where the 1.9.3 version of ruby was installed along side version 1.9.1 and therefore errors arrose when trying to generate the site.</p>

<p>To fix Ruby on Ubuntu, I loaded up Synaptic package manager and removed all Ruby packages and anything related, such as gem and bundler.  Then I installed the package ruby2.0 along with the docs and dev packages for that version.  With only the latest version of Ruby installed, Octopress worked perfectly.</p>

<p>I look forward to sharing my further experiences blogging with Octopress</p>

<p>Thank you.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
