<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: octopress | jr0cket - community developer]]></title>
  <link href="http://jr0cket.github.io/octopress-project/blog/categories/octopress/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jr0cket.github.io/octopress-project/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-24T21:23:20+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://jr0cket.github.io/octopress-project/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[John Stevenson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First blog post ever - awesome]]></title>
    <link href="http://jr0cket.github.io/octopress-project/blog/2014/03/first-blog-post-ever-awesome/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-03T00:08:42+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://jr0cket.github.io/octopress-project/blog/2014/03/first-blog-post-ever-awesome</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is the first blog post of many in my adventures in learning how to publish a blog using Octopress.</p>

<p>As a developer I want a lightweight tool to create and easily publish content interesting to other developers in the community.  Although I can write HTML, CSS and JavaScript for webapps, I dont want to be slowed down writing these things when I am doing creative writing.</p>

<p>Using Octopress, which is a blogging framework on top of Jekyll, I can write my content using Markdown.  As Markdown is just simple text with a few characters and indents used for formating, I can focus on the writing and make it as appealing as I can.  I dont get distracted by the visual layout of the content and a standard design for the blog is consistently applied.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The only challenge I had intially was to get a working copy of Ruby running on my Ubuntu laptop.  Jekyll and therefore Octopress requires Ruby version 1.9.3 or greater and Unfortunately I seemed to have a mix of 1.9.1 and 1.9.3.  In Ubuntu 13.10 there is a strange stiuation where the 1.9.3 version of ruby was installed along side version 1.9.1 and therefore errors arrose when trying to generate the site.</p>

<p>To fix Ruby on Ubuntu, I loaded up Synaptic package manager and removed all Ruby packages and anything related, such as gem and bundler.  Then I installed the package ruby2.0 along with the docs and dev packages for that version.  With only the latest version of Ruby installed, Octopress worked perfectly.</p>

<p>I look forward to sharing my further experiences blogging with Octopress</p>

<p>Thank you.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
